Inside every one of us is a special talent waiting to
come out. The trick is finding it.
Billy Elliot is a drama, comedy, music film directed by Stephen Daldry.
County Durham, England, 1984.
The miners' strike has started and the police have started coming up from
Bethnal Green, starting a class war with the lower classes suffering.
Caught in the middle of the conflict is 11-year old Billy Elliot, who, after leaving his boxing club
for the day, stumbles upon a ballet class and finds out that he's naturally talented.
He practices with his teacher Mrs.
Wilkinson for an upcoming audition in Newcastle-upon Tyne
for the royal Ballet school in London.
Billy Elliot, played by Jamie Bell.
Jackie Elliot, played by Gary Lewis.
Mrs Wilkinson, played by Julie Walters.
Grandma, played by Jean Heywood.
Tony Elliot, played by Jamie Draven.
Michael Caffrey, played by Stuart Wells.
Billy Elliot is a 2000 British coming-of-age drama film
directed by Stephen Daldry and written by Lee Hall.
Set in County Durham in North East England during the 1984–1985 miners' strike,
the film is about a working-class boy who has a passion for ballet.
His father objects, based on negative stereotypes of male ballet dancers.
The film stars Jamie Bell as 11-year-old Billy, Gary Lewis as his father, Jamie
Draven as Billy's older brother, and Julie Walters as his ballet teacher.
Adapted from a play called Dancer by Lee Hall,
development on the film began in 1999.
Around 2,000 boys were considered for the role of Billy before Bell was chosen.
Filming began in the North East of England in August 1999.
Greg Brenman and Jon Finn served as producers, while
Stephen Warbeck composed the film's score.
Billy Elliot is a co-production among BBC Films, Tiger
Aspect Pictures and Working Title Films.
The film premiered at the 2000 Cannes Film Festival,  and began a wider theatrical release in the United
Kingdom on 29 September 2000 by Universal Pictures through United International Pictures.
Billy Elliot received positive critical response and commercial success,
earning $109.3 million worldwide on a $5 million budget.
At the 54th British Academy Film Awards, the film won
three of thirteen award nominations.
Jamie Bell became the youngest winner of Best Actor in a Leading Role.
The film also earned three nominations at the 73rd Academy Awards for Best
Director, Best Original Screenplay and Best Actress in a Supporting Role.
In 2001, the film was adapted as a novel by Melvin Burgess.
The story was also adapted for the West End stage as Billy
Elliot the Musical, first produced in 2005.
It opened in Australia in 2007 and on Broadway in New York City in 2008.
The film explores themes of dancing, friendship,
dreams, dancing class, northern england.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.